Guide to the Doris Duke Papers on the Rough Point Residence, 1922-1997 RL.01433
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Records, 1922-1997
  - Photograph inventory, Blue Room, 1980 Dec (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Photograph inventory, Blue Room and bath, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Photograph inventory, Dining Room, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Photograph inventory, Great Hall, 1980, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Photograph inventory, Green Room, 1980, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Photograph inventory, Ladies Room, 1980 Mar (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Photograph inventory, Main Entrance, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Photograph inventory, 1969, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Photograph inventory, Miss Duke's Room and Bath, 1980, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Photograph inventory, Morning Room, 1980 Apr (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Photograph inventory, Morning Room (A), 1984 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Photograph inventory, Morning Room (B), 1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Photograph inventory, Music Room, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - NRF Inventory Cards, 1969-1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photograph inventory, Pink Room-Lamp, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Photograph inventory, Pink Room, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Photograph inventory, Pink Room, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Photograph inventory, Pine Room, 1980 Dec (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Photograph inventory, 2nd Floor Hall (C), 1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Photograph inventory, 2nd Floor Hall (D), 1984 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Photograph inventory, 2nd Floor Hall, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Photograph inventory, Staircase, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Photograph inventory, Stairhall, 1980 Mar (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Photograph inventory, Stairhall, 1980 Apr (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Photograph inventory, Stairhall, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Photograph inventory, Stairhall with negatives, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Photograph inventory, Yellow Room, 1980 Dec (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Photograph inventory, Yellow Room-Leather Box Inventory Card with negatives, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Photograph inventory, Yellow Room, 1980 Feb (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Photograph inventory, Yellow Room, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Photograph inventory, Miscellaneous Room Photos, 1974-1984 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous art and furniture labels, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of furniture and cup and saucer, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence regarding restoration, preservation, and waterproofing of "Rough Point House" by Universal Restoration, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Photocopy of "Furniture and Works of Art in The Elms, Newport Residence of Miss Julia A. Berwind" to be sold by Parke-Bernet Galleries. Includes inventory cards with photographs, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and work reports regarding Rough Point, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Architectural Records, 1923, 1970-1975, Approximately 15 items
  Includes blueprints, diazo and vellum. A majority of the records are blueprints dating from 1923 detailing alterations and additions to the Rough Point residence as designed by the Horace Trumbauer firm. The drawings include plans,elevations, and sections of the interior of the home. Also included in the records are plans, elevations, and details of windows dating from the 1970s, presumably created for renovations to the estate.
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke Newport, RI, Basement Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan-Jun. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke Newport, RI, First Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan-Jun. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke Newport, RI, Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan-Jun. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke Newport, RI, Third Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan-Jun. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke Newport, RI, Section Thru Great Hall Toward Entrance Gable, North East Elevation, South East Elevation. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923 Jan-Jun]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke Newport, RI, North West Elevation, South West Elevation. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923 Jan-Jun]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations & Additions to Rough Point Residence for J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #1-Basement Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Revised 1923 Jan 11. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations & Additions to Rough Point Residence for J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #2-First Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Revised 1923 Jan 11. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations & Additions to Rough Point Residence for J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #3-Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [Revised 1923 Jan 11]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations & Additions to Rough Point Residence for J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #4-Third Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [Revised 1923 Jan 11]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder C1D10F16)
  - Alterations and Additions to "Rough Point" Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Electric Light Layout First Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP1)
  - Alterations and Additions to "Rough Point" Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Electric Light Layout Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP1)
  - Alterations and Additions to "Rough Point" Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Electric Light Layout Third Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP1)
  - Alterations and Additions to "Rough Point" Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Electric Light Layout Basement Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP1)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #15-Basement Windows. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Oct 30. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #30-Section on Line A.A. and Second Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #29-First Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #27-Details of Chimney and Fireplace, Old Section. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan 7. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #27-Details of Music and Drawing Room Fire Places. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Dec 13. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #11. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Nov 1, revised 1922 Dec 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Alterations and Additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #12-First Floor Plan. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Nov 1. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - Entrance Gates to Driveway, Estate of J.B. Duke, Rough Point, Newport, RI. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP2)
  - [Preliminary Plan of Newport Residence]. Horatio Buckenham, landscape engineer. 1923 Jul 1. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP3)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rough Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #9- Details of North East End of Music Room. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Nov 27. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP3)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rough Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #7- South-East Elevation of Music Room Wing. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Nov 28. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP3)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rough Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #8- North Western Elevation of Music Room. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Oct 30. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP3)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rough Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #9- North-East Elevation of Music Room. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1922 Oct 31. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP3)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rough Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #10- Elevation of Windows. Horace Trumbauer, architect. undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP3)
  - Alterations to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Sheet No. 35-Plan Showing Wall Lines and Openings in Masonry. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan 18. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP4)
  - Alterations to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Sheet No. 28-Plan Showing Wall Lines and Openings in Masonry. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan 25. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP4)
  - Alterations to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Sheet No. 39-Plan Showing Wall Lines and Openings in Masonry. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP4)
  - Entrance Gates to Driveway, Estate of J.B. Duke, Rough Point, Newport, RI. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP4)
  - Certain Land of Doris Duke Cromwell - Rough Point. Malcolm E. Barrett, professional engineer, R. C. Crisson and J. Barker. 1975 Dec 3. Vellum. (Oversize-folder RP5)
  - Cliff Walk Shore Restoration & Protection - Department of the Army. S.W. Laurin. 1975 Aug 18. Vellum. (Oversize-folder RP5)
  - Rough Point - Roof Plan. Universal Restorations Inc./BW. 1970 May 8. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP5)
  - Rough Point - North Elevation, South Elevation, East Elevation. Universal Restorations Inc. 1970 May 8. Diazo. (Oversize-folder RP5)
  - Rough Point - Window Type 1; Windows Type 2, 3, 9, 10, 11; Windows Types 4, 8, 12, 13; Solarium Door Type 14; Section AA; Section CC; Section BB. Universal Restorations Inc. 1970 May 8. Diazo. (Oversize-folder RP5)
  - Rough Point - Window Types 5,6,7; Window Types A, B, C, D, and E; Window F; Window Type G (Double Door), Window Type H (Single Door). Universal Restorations Inc. 1970 May 8. Diazo. (Oversize-folder RP5)
  - Detail Elevation of Great Hall to Morning Room and Stair Hall. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Drawing Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail of Morning Room Ceiling. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail of Stair Hall. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Sitting Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Mrs. Duke's Bedroom. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Great Hall to Drawing Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Music Room to Drawing Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail of 1st Floor Stair Hall Ceiling. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Men's Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Morning Room to Stair Hall. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail of 2nd Floor Stair Hall. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Loggia to Drawing Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Dining Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Governess Room D. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP6)
  - Detail Elevation of Daughter's Room E. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Guest Room A. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Mr. Duke's Bedroom. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail of Great Hall Ceiling. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation Guest Room C. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Stair Hall to Dining Room, Corridor and Entrance Hall. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail of Proposed Scheme, Mr. Duke's Bathroom. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Vestibule. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail of Dining Hall Ceiling. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Guest Room E. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation, Floor Plan, and Ceiling of Entrance Hall. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail of Loggia Floor Plan. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail of Great Hall Floor. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Guest Room B. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail Elevation of Ladies' Room. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Detail of 1st Floor Stair Hall Floor. White Allom & Co., interior design. 1923 Mar 29. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP7)
  - Alteration and additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #37-Section thru new Wing. Horace Trumbauer, architect. [1923 Jan 24]. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Residence of Mr. J. B. Duke, Newport, RI: Second On Line B.B. Horace Trumbauer, architect. 1923 Jan 30. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Alteration and additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #32-Details for Rough Openings, First Floor. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Alteration and additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #38-Plan Showing Wall Lines and Opening in Masonry. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Alteration and additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #36-Stalls. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Alteration and additions to Rough Point Residence for Mr. J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, #354-Details for Openings Second Floor. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Outline Planting Plan, Location of Present Entrance as Change in Drive. Undated. Blueprint with colored pencil. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - [Security System, Rough Point]. Home & Commercial Security Inc. 1988 May 15. Diazo with marker. (Oversize-folder RP8)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rocky Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, First Floor Plan-Scheme A. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-box Arch 1, Folder RP9)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rocky Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, First Floor Plan of Residence as Now Existing. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-box Arch 1, Folder RP9)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rocky Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, 3rd Floor Plan of residence as now existing. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-box Arch 1, Folder RP10)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rocky Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Second floor plan and Second floor of residence now existing. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-box Arch 1, Folder RP10)
  - Proposed Alterations to "Rocky Point" Residence of J.B. Duke, Newport, RI, Ocean Front Elevation and North elevation as now existing. Horace Trumbauer, architect. Undated. Blueprint. (Oversize-box Arch 1, Folder RP10)